Section A, Directions.
this section, you will hear two long conversations.
At the end of each conversation, you will hear four questions.
Both the conversation and the questions will be spoken only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose the best answer from the four choices
marked A, B, C, and D.
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1, with a single line through the
centre. Conversation 1.
Tell me, Peter, what makes Harrods so famous?
Well, it's the biggest department store in the UK, and its food hall and Egyptian
hall are very famous.
People come to Harrods just to see them.
What is special about the food hall?
it sells many different kinds of For example, it has 250 kinds of cheese from all
over the world, and more than 180 kinds of bread.
Customers also love all the different kinds of chocolate.
They buy 100 tons every year.
That's amazing. And why is the Egyptian hall so famous?
Well, when people see it, they feel they're in another world.
It looks like an Egyptian building from 4,000 years ago, and it sells beautiful
objects. They are not 4,000 years old, of course.
Is it true that Harrods produces its own electricity?
Yes, it does.
70%, enough for a small town.
To light the outside of the building, we use 11,500 light bulbs.
Really? Tell me, how many customers do you have on an average day, and how much do
they spend? About 30,000 people come on an average day.
But during the sales, the number increases to 300,000 customers a day.
How much do they spend?
Well, on average, customers spend about 1.5 million pounds a day.
The record for one day is 9 million pounds.
9 million pounds in one day?
Yes, on the first day of the January sales.
Harrods says it sells everything to everybody everywhere.
Is that really true?
Ah, yes, of course.
Absolutely everything.
Questions 1 to 4 are based on the conversation you have just had.
Question 1. What is the food hall of Harrods noted for?
Question 2. What does the Egyptian hall seem like to the customers?
Question 2. What What may customers find surprising about Harrods?
Question 4. About how many customers come to Harrods on an average day?
Conversation 2. Hello and welcome to our program, Working Abroad.
Our guest this evening is a Londoner who lives and works in Italy.
Her name's Susan Hill.
Susan, welcome to the program.
You live in Florence.
How long have you been living there?
Since 1982. But when I went there in 1982, I planned to stay for only six months.
Why did you change your mind?
Well, I'm a designer.
I design leather goods, mainly shoes and handbags.
Soon after I arrived in Florence, I got a job with one of Italy's top fashion
houses, Ferragamo. So I decided to stay.
How lucky! Do you still work for Ferragamo?
No, I've been a freelance designer for quite a long time now, since 1988 in fact.
So does that mean you design for several different companies now?
Yes, that's right.
I've designed many fashion items for a number of Italian companies.
And during the last four years, I've also been designing for the British company
Burberry. What have you been designing for them?
Mostly handbags and small leather goods.
Has the fashion industry in Italy changed since 1982?
Oh, yes. It has become a lot more competitive, because the quality of products from
other countries has improved a But the Italian quality and design is still world
famous. And do you ever think of returning to live in England?
No, not really.
Working in Italy is more interesting.
I also love the Mediterranean sun and the Italian lifestyle.
Well, thank you for talking to us, Susan.
My pleasure. Questions 5 to 8 are based on the conversation you have just heard.
Question 5. Where does this talk most probably take place?
Question 6. What was the woman's original plan when she went to Florence?
Question 7. What has the woman been doing for a living since 1988?
Question 8. What do we learn about the change in Italy's fashion industry?
Question 8. Section B.
Directions. this section, you will hear two passages.
At the end of each passage, you will hear three or four questions.
Both the passage and the questions will be spoken only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose the best answer from the four choices
marked A, B, C and D.
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1 with a single line through the
centre. Passage 1.
Many days seem to bring numerous tasks and responsibilities, all of which apparently
must be tackled right away.
You spend a day putting out files, but by the end of the day, you haven't
accomplished any of the really important things you set out to do.
In desperation, you draft a to -do list, but most days you can make little progress
with it. When you look at the list each morning, a big fat cloud of doom is right at
the top. Those difficult, complex, important tasks are so crucial to get done and so
easy to avoid.
Plenty of us create a to -do list to address feelings of being overwhelmed, but we
rarely use these tools to their best effect.
They wind up being guilt -provoking reminders of the fact that we are overcommitted
and losing control of our priorities.
According to Timothy Piccio, a professor of at Carleton University in Ottawa,
people often draw up a to -do list and then that's it.
The list itself becomes the day's achievement, allowing us to feel we've done
something useful without taking on any real work.
In fact, drawing up the becomes a way of avoiding the work itself.
Too often, the list is seen as the accomplishment for the day, reducing the
immediate guilt of not working on the tasks at hand by investing energy in the list,
says Piccio. When a list is used like this, it's simply another way in which we lie
to ourselves. Questions 9 to 11 are based on the passage you have just heard.
Question 9. What is the problem that troubles many people nowadays, according to the
speaker? Question 10.
According to the speaker, what do many people do to cope with their daily tasks?
Question 11. According to psychologist Timothy Piccio, what do people find by the
end of the day?
Passage 2. In many stressful situations, the body's responses can improve our
performance. We become more energetic, more alert, better able to take effective
action. But when stress is encountered continually, the body's reactions are more
likely The be harmful than helpful to us.
The continual speeding up of bodily reactions and the production of stress -related
hormones seem to make people more susceptible to heart disease.
And stress reactions can reduce the disease -fighting effectiveness of the body's
immune system, thereby increasing susceptibility to illnesses ranging from colds to
cancer. Stress may also contribute to disease in less direct ways, by influencing
moods and behavior.
People under stress may become anxious or depressed, and as a result may eat too
much or too little, have sleep difficulties, or fail to exercise.
These behavioral changes may in turn be harmful to their health.
In addition, people are more likely to pay attention to certain bodily sensations,
such as aches and pains when they are under stress, and to think that they're sick.
If the person were not under stress, the same bodily sensations might not be
perceived as symptoms, and the person might continue to feel well.
Some researchers have suggested that assuming the role of a sick person is one way
in which certain people try to cope with stress.
Instead of dealing with the stressful situation directly, these people fall sick.
After all, it is often more acceptable in our society to be sick and to seek medical
help than it is to admit that one cannot cope with the stresses of life.
Questions 12 to 15 are based on the passage you have just heard.
Question 12. What does the speaker say about people who encounter stress once in a
while? Question 13.
What does the speaker say frequent stress reactions may lead to?
Question 14. What are people more likely to do when they are under stress?
Question 15. What does the passage mainly talk about?
Section C. Directions.
this section, you will hear three recordings of lectures or talks, followed by three
or four questions.
The recordings will be played only once.
After you hear a question, you must Choose the best answer from the four choices
marked A, B, C and D.
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1 with a single line through the
center. Recording 1.
Everyday conversation is essential to several aspects of life, such as
relationships, business and personal, building trust and credibility, and creating a
pleasurable experience for yourself and others.
It comes as no surprise, therefore, that conversation skills are one of the most
basic skills needed to function well in everyday society.
One of the most important conversation skills for you to have is the ability to
avoid using offensive or hurtful language.
This becomes especially difficult when you are not aware that the words you use are
actually considered hurtful.
Slang words commonly used by the younger generation can also be unknowingly
offensive. To assist with this confusion, here are a few common words or phrases
which you may or may not know are actually hurtful.
The first one is I don't care.
This is a very common phrase for someone to say in a variety of situations, and it
is obvious that it can easily offend.
It is never nice to say that you don't care about something or someone, even in a
joking manner. To those who are a bit more sensitive, they might take your words
more seriously than you think.
Altogether, it is best to assume that this phrase is offensive in most situations.
The second is it was just a joke.
If a person has trouble tolerating whatever you just said, they won't believe you
say you weren't serious.
No matter how close you are as friends or family, if you make an offensive comment
and expect them to take it as a joke, it might be a little too much to ask.
Although you may have had good intentions, it always pays to be careful about what
you say out loud, especially if you know the person is a little bit sensitive.
third is never mind, you don't get it.
Nobody likes being left out of the loop, and used in the wrong context, this can
make it sound like you left the person out on purpose.
Although you may have only meant for it to be a quick dismissal of a subject, it
could come off as rude, which destroys relationships rather than maintains them.
Next time, try providing an explanation, no matter how brief.
The fourth is what's the point?
Although you may have asked this from a viewpoint of curiosity, it is easy for this
statement to sound offensive.
Depending on the sensitivity or the person and the circumstance, it might sound like
you are dismissing their explanation before they even try explaining.
It sounds rude, and there are many more polite ways to ask about the purpose of an
action. Questions 16 to 19 are based on the recording you have just had.
Question 16. What is one of the most important conversation skills according to the
speaker? Question 17.
What does the speaker say about sensitive people?
Question 18. Which of the following common words may hurt others?
Question 19. What does the speaker suggest we do, instead of saying, never mind, you
don't get it?
Recording 2. More and more people around the world are using wireless or mobile
devices. In some countries, smartphones and other mobile devices serve as
replacements for the traditional desktop computer.
This increase in mobile device usage has also led to the growth of the mobile gaming
industry. Experts say the industry will be worth more than $11 billion this year.
Early computers were too slow to process the amount of data needed for realistic
pictures, sound, and special effects.
But processors soon became faster and less costly.
Manufacturers saw there was money to be made, so they developed machines designed
only for games.
Now smartphones and other mobile devices have created new ways to play games.
Large companies compete in an expanding gaming market.
Gamers and game developers recently showed and tested their products at the
Electronics Entertainment Exhibition in Los Angeles, California.
The event is called E3 for short.
Gaming industry leaders like Xbox and PlayStation demonstrated new products at E3.
Famous Americans like comedian Conan O attended the event.
AppAnnie, based in San Francisco, California, is a mobile gaming market research
company. AppAnnie's Marcos Sanchez says companies that develop games for mobile
devices are making huge profits.
Yoshio Osaki is the top vice president of the International Development Group.
The official says new companies are doing very well with all the different ways to
provide people with games.
The video games are not just about the console anymore, and you see a lot of cross
-pollination and hybridization across Sony, Microsoft, Nintendo, EA, and Activation,
etc. Many of the gaming companies depend on loyal gamers for fresh ideas, and age is
unimportant to some companies.
Michael Saman is a 17 -year -old Facebook employee.
spoke recently with Voice of America's Spanish service about some of his Facebook
responsibilities. I will be working on a system called PaaS, which is part of
Facebook and works with many applications,
and they all connect together through what Facebook does and what the company within
Facebook. PaaS also does, Saman said.
PaaS software is designed to help others develop even more applications for mobile
devices. Questions 20 to 22 are based on the recording you have just heard.
Question 20. Why did manufacturers develop machines designed only for games?
Question 21. How is the business of developing games for mobile devices?
Question 22. How do gaming companies benefit from loyal gamers?
Recording 3. People all over the world today are beginning to hear and learn more
and more about the problem of
Pollution is caused either by man's release of completely new and often artificial
substances into into the environment, or by releasing greatly increased amounts of
natural substances such as oil from oil tankers into the sea.
The whole industrial process which makes many of the goods and machines we need and
use in our daily life is bound to create a number of waste products which upset the
environmental balance or the ecological balance as it is also known.
Many of these waste products can be prevented or disposed of sensibly, but clearly,
while more and more new and complex goods are produced, there will be new, dangerous
wastes to be disposed of, for example, the waste products from nuclear power
stations. Many people therefore see pollution as only part of a larger and more
complex problem, that is, the whole process of industrial production and consumption
of goods. Others, again, see the problem mainly in connection with agriculture,
where new methods are helping farmers grow more and more on their land to feed our
ever -increasing populations.
However, the land itself, if gradually becoming worn out as it is being used in some
cases too heavily, cannot restore the balance.
Whatever the underlying reasons are, there is no doubt that much of the pollution
caused could be controlled if only companies, individuals and governments would make
more efforts. In the home, there is an obvious need to control litter and waste.
Food comes wrapped up three or four times in packages that all have to be disposed
of. Drinks are increasingly sold in bottles or tins, which cannot be reused.
This not only causes a litter problem, but also is a great waste of resources in
terms of glass, metals and paper.
Advertising has helped this process by persuading many of us not only to buy things
we neither want nor need, but also to throw away much of what we do buy.
Pollution and waste continue to be a problem everyone can help to solve by cutting
out unnecessary buying, excess consumption and careless disposal of the products we
use in our daily life.
Questions 23 to 25 are based on the recording you have just heard.
Question 23. to the recording, what may cause pollution?
Question 24. On what condition can farmland restore the balance?
Question 25. According to the speaker, what can we do to solve the problem of
pollution and waste?
This is the end.
End of listening comprehension.